Rudolph Schaeffer
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, circa 1910-1987, Series 4:; (Boxes 2-6, 15; 3.8 linear ft.)
  - Writings by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1910-1987, 4.1:
    Writings by Rudolph Schaeffer include manuscripts for published and unpublished articles and drafts, notes, and manuscripts of several unpublished books including Collected Lectures of Rudolph Schaeffer on Color and Design, Color and Design, Prismatic Color Theory, and Rhythmo-Chromatics, all undated. Diaries include a volume recording Schaeffer's 1936 trip to Japan. 42 volumes of journals, compiled between 1954 and 1987 become progressively more introspective and focused on the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design. They contain entries on a wide range of subjects including lists of errands, invitation lists, class notes, drafts of letters, notes including staff assignments and staff meetings, autobiographical notes and reminiscences, and musings on religion and philosophy. Also extant are notes and texts for lectures and talks given at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design and many other venues, as well as notes on philosophy, color, and miscellaneous topics.
    - Articles, 1918-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Books (unpublished) (Box 2)
      - Collected Lectures of Rudolph Schaeffer on Color and Design, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Color and Design, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Prismatic Color Theory, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Rhythmo-Chromatics, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 52-54)
    - Diaries (Box 3)
      - Vol. 1: Japan, July 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Vols. 2-3, (see: Box 15) (Box 3)
    - Journals (Box 3)
      - Vol. 1: Dec. 6, 1954 – Oct. 6, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 2: Oct. 8, 1955 – Oct. 23, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 3: Nov. 1, 1956 – Dec. 23, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 4: Jan. 13, 1958 – Jan. 24, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 5: Jan. 29, 1959 – Jan. 1, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 6: Nov. 21, 1959 – May 2, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 7: May 7 - Dec. 9, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 8: Jan. 5 – July 2, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 9: July 4, 1961 – Feb. 2, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 10: Feb. 5 – Aug. 7, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 11: Sept. 5, 1962 – March 26, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 12: March 26 – Dec. 15, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 13: Jan. 4 – Sept. 16, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 14: Sept. 19, 1964 – May 18, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 15: June 1, 1965 – March 29, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 16: March 29, 1966 – Jan. 18, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 17: Jan. 3, 1967 – Jan. 31, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 18: Feb. 12, 1968 – March 3, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 19: March 8, 1969 – June 4, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 20: March 4, 1969 – Jan. 19, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Vol. 21: June 9 – Dec. 15, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Vol. 22: Jan. 5, 1971 – Feb. 7, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 23: Jan. 31 – Nov. 13, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 24: Jan. 15 – May 14, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 25: May 15 – Sept. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 26: Sept. 23, 1973 – Feb. 26, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 27: March 4 – Dec. 16, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 28: Jan 6 – Aug. 20, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 29: Sept. 19, 1975 – March 11, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 30: June 28, 1976 – March 29, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 31: Aug. 10, 1977 – July 1, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 32: Sept. 8, 1978 – Sept. 16, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 33: Sept. 21, 1979 – May 12, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 34: July 1980 – Dec. 1, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 35: Jan. 19 – June 16, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 36: Aug. 11, 1982 – Dec. 20, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 37: Aug. 1 – Nov. 16, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 38: Jan. 1 – March 16, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 39: April 18 – Sept. 13, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 40: Nov. 23, 1984 – Feb. 5, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 41: Aug. 10, 1985 – Jan. 12, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 42: March 29, 1986 – March 9, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Lectures (Box 5)
      - Pre-dating Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, circa 1910, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1920s-1980s, undated, (17 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-39)
      - Other Venues, 1920s-1983, undated, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 40-45)
    - Lists of Faculty and Staff, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1930-1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Notebooks (Box 5)
      - Vols. 1-4, 1920, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Vol. 5 ("Quotations," "Basic Principles," "Application of Principles," Miscellaneous), 1935, 1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Notes on Color, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Notes on Philosophy, 1937-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1931, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Radio Talks, 1935-1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - School Catalog (draft), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Diaries, (see also Box 3) (Box 15 (sol))
      - Vol. 2: Jan. - Aug., 1940 (Box 15 (sol))
      - Vol. 3: Aug. - Dec., 1940, 1941 (Box 15 (sol))
  - Writings by Other Authors, 1923-1987, 4.2:
    Writings by other authors are about Rudolph Schaeffer and his school. Included are reminiscences of former students, student essays, transcripts of oral history interviews conducted with Schaeffer, and Doris A. McMillan’s notes of classes attended at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design between 1923 and 1946.
    - Angelo, Ann B. "Rudolph Schaeffer: A Memoir (An Archival Image Applying Oral History Techniques)," M. A. Thesis, John F. Kennedy University (Museum Studies/Museology Program), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Baglin, M. "Colour (one of R. Schaeffer’s pupils looks at snow.)," Poem, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cuddy, John. "The Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design – Which is in San Francisco," undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - McMillan, Doris A. Class Notes, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1923-1946, (9 vols. in 3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
      - Vol. 1: "Color and Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer, 1923 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 2: "Color" with Rudolph Schaeffer, 1926 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 3: "Color Notes" (from Light and Color by M. Luckish), 1928 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 4: "Design" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Plastic Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dyes" with Miss Henry and Welland Lathrop, 1928, 1930 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 5: "Plastic Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Art in Public School" with Miss Lewis, 1930 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 6: "Aesthetic Appreciation" with Rudolph Schaeffer, 1932 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 7: "Flower Arrangement" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dyes and Application to Textiles" (research notes), 1930, undated (Box 6)
      - Vol. 8: "Round the Color Wheel with Rudolph Schaeffer"; "Costume Design" with Marie Leonard, 1944 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 9: "Free Brush" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dimensional Design," 1946 (Box 6)
    - Robbins, Beverly. Untitled Talk (about studying at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, delivered at University of California Symposium), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Roos, Robert de. "Rudolph Schaeffer," circa 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Student Essays, 1938, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Various Authors (Box 6)
      - Lectures, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1929-1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Press Releases (Rudolph Schaeffer and Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design), 1928-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Welch, Nell True (edited by and foreword by Rudolph Schaeffer). Sunset’s Flower Arrangement Book, circa 1942 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Unknown. Poem, "An Abstract Principle Learned in Schaeffer’s School of DESIGN," undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Artwork, 1911-1957, Series 5:; (Boxes 6, 15, OV 17; 0.3 linear ft.)
  Additional artwork, mainly drawings by Rudolph Schaeffer and others, is among the subject files (Series 3) and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  5.1: Artwork by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1911-1957
  5.2: Artwork by Other Artists, undated
  - Artwork By Rudolph Schaeffer, 1911-1957, 5.1:
    - Calligraphy, 1916, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Christmas Cards, 1927, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Color Studies (spiral bound volume), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Designs Illustrating Notan (with notes; on cards), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Designs, Drawings, Sketches, 1914-1957, undated, (see also: Box 15) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Designs, Sketches and Notes (original collation, removed from 3-ring binder), undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Furniture Designs, undated, (see: Box 15) (Box 6)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 6)
      - Vol. 1: Flower Arrangements (includes miscellaneous notes), 1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Vol. 2: Sketches (with notes), undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Vol. 3: Furniture Designs, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Vol. 4: Sketchbook (with notes), undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Designs and Drawings, 1911, undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Furniture Designs, undated (Box 15 (sol))
  - Artwork by Other Artists, undated, 5.2:
    Artwork by others includes designs, probably by students including Enid Alpers, Mary A. Baird, and Margaret Paxton.
    - Designs, 1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Drawing (by Piercy), undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Painting (by unknown), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Drawing, "Perspective from Northwest Corner, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design…" (by J. B. Webb), 1958 (Box OV 17)
- Scrapbooks, 1933-1976, Series 6:; (Boxes 6, 14; 0.5 linear ft.)
  Scrapbooks consist of 7 volumes containing printed material, photographs, letters, and a small amount of artwork. They document Rudolph Schaeffer’s career, his school and former students, and the San Francisco art scene. Two volumes are devoted to specific subjects: the East-West Gallery (vol. 3, 1950), Rudolph Schaeffer’s 90th Birthday and the 50th Anniversary of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design (vol. 7, 1976).
  - Vol. 1, (see Box 14) (Box 6)
  - Vol. 2, 1937-1943, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Vol. 3, East-West Gallery, 1950, (disbound loose leaf notebook; original collation) (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Vols. 4-6, (see: Box 14) (Box 6)
  - Vol. 7, Rudolph Schaeffer’s 90th Birthday and 50th Anniversary of the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Vol. 1, 1933-1940 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Vol. 4, Rudolph Schaeffer’s 90th Birthday and 50th Anniversary of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1976 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Vol. 5, "Of passing interest and perhaps much more in 1971-1972," 1971-1972 (Box 14 (sol))
  - Vol. 6, "Of passing interest and perhaps much, much more," 1973-1975 (Box 14 (sol))
- Sound Recordings, 1949-1986, Series 7:; (Boxes 11-13; 1.8 linear ft.)
  Recordings consist of audio cassettes and reels, along with a small number of transcripts. Most recordings are lectures by Schaeffer and others delivered at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design. Other recordings include Rudolph Schaeffer playing the piano, and "Rudolph Schaeffer Day," a city-wide event in San Francisco commemorating Schaeffer's 100th birthday.
  The series is arranged into 3 subseries:
  7.1: Transcripts, undated
  7.2: Cassettes, 1979-1986
  7.3: Reels, 1949-1973
  - Transcripts, undated, 7.1:
    - Transcripts of Selected Recordings (1937-1980), undated, (4 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 1-4)
  - Cassettes, 1979-1986, 7.1:
    - "Color" (parts 2-15), Lectures by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1979-1980, (3 folders, 14 cassettes) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 5-7)
    - "Rudolph;" "Rudolph Schaeffer Day;" "R. S. Piano," "R. S. at Home," 1986, undated, (4 cassettes) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Lectures (?) by Rudolph Schaeffer, March 24-May 12, 1980, (4 cassettes) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Reels, 1949-1973, 7.3:
    Series contains approximately 40 recordings on 35 sound tape reels (1/4 in. tape). Unless otherwise noted, reels are 7" in diameter.
    Sound recordings are arranged in rough alphabetical order by title. Where different subjects were taped on the same reel, they are listed together in order to reflect the physical arrangement of the interviews on the reels.
    All of the sound tape reels have been digitized for research access.
    - Art and General Semantics, lecture by Haridas Chaudhuri, 1959 Feb 16, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 1)
    - Art in the Home, lecture by William Gaskin, circa 1960-1969 Jul 19, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 2)
    - Awareness of form and color, introduction, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel: 5 in.) (Box 12, Item 3)
    - Awareness, part 1, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1960 March 24, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 4)
    - Awareness, part 2, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1960 March 24, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 5)
    - Art of Arrangement, second and third lectures by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1960 October 6 and 1960 November 3, (1 side of sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 6)
    - Beatnick Poetry, lecture by Dr. Frederick Spielberg, 1960 February 18, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 7)
    - Chinese Art Structure, summer seminar (Box 12)
      - Line, Outline, and Form; lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 July 25, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 8)
        (Last 26 minutes of side 2 contains an excerpt of a lecture on meditation and creativity by Haridas Chaudhuri, not dated)
      - Form and Color, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 July 26, (part of 1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 9)
      - Color and Revealing of Art Objects, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 July 27, (part of 1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 10)
      - Chinese Calligraphy and its Influence on Chinese Painting, lecture by William Wu, 1973 July 27, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 11)
      - Space, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 July 30, (part of 1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 12)
      - Chinese Painters, lecture by Howard Rogers, 1973 July 30, (part of 1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 13)
      - Ten Bamboo Hall Prints, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 July 31, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 14)
      - Holistic Philosophy, lecture by Haridas Chaudhuri, 1973 August 1, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 15)
      - Finale, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1973 August 3, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 16)
      - Six Courses of Chinese Art, lecture by William Wu1973 August 3, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 17)
    - Color, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffercirca 1950-1959, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 18)
    - Color, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel: 5 in.) (Box 12, Item 19)
    - Contemporary Weavers: Light and Life in Weaving, lecture by Rudolph Scaheffer, 1960 January 9, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 20)
    - Design, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 23)
    - Interior Design and Color, excerpt of lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 24)
    - Interior Design: Fine Art, Space, Light; lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1959 October 1, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 25)
    - Unidentified lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 26)
    - Modern Art, lecture by unidentified speakercirca 1960-1969, (2 sound tape reels) (Box 12, Item 27)
    - Oriental Art Summer Seminar, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 28)
    - Picasso'a Yoga, lecture by Frederic Spielberg, 1959 March 19, (2 sound tape reels) (Box 12, Item 29)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design meeting, 1961 March 6, (2 sound tape reels) (Box 12, Item 30)
      (Attendees include Rudolph Schaeffer, Bill Goghen, Bill Allen, Jo Sinel, and Fred Frey)
    - Plans for World Improvement, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 31)
    - Principles of Order, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1950-1959, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 32)
    - Principles of Design, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1959 October 29, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 33)
    - Elements of Design, 1960 September 27, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 34)
    - Recorded Greeting to Students from Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1960-1969, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 12, Item 35)
    - School Architecture, lecture by Mario Ciampi, 1957 July 26, (2 sound tape reels) (Box 13, Item 1)
      (Reel 2 contains 16 minutes of a lecture on Indian dance by an unidentified speaker at the end of side 2)
    - Space in Design, lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1950-1959, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 13, Item 2)
    - Test Reel, circa 1960, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 13, Item 3)
    - Test Reel, 1972, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 13, Item 4)
    - Blank Reels, circa 1950-1976, (3 sound tape reels) (Box 13, Item 5)
      (1 of the blank reels was labeled "Japanese Rock Poems," and dated October 15, 1959. The other 2 blank reels were unlabeled)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1905-1986, Series 8:; (Box 7; 0.5 linear ft.)
  Among the miscellaneous records are color samples for various Schaeffer projects and transcripts of various interviews conducted with Schaeffer and a meeting of the school staff. Guest books include those for Schaeffer's 99th and 100th birthday parties.
  - Artifact – "Piece of colored stucco picked up from the ground, a specimen of beautiful blue green color, Peking, summer 1936"), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Color Samples (for textiles, store and/or residential interiors, and unidentified purposes), 1947-1948 (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Guest Books (Box 7)
    - Guest Book of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1934-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer’s 100th Birthday, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer’s Birthday (loose pages), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Policies, 1905-1915 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stock Certificate, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Transcripts (Box 7)
    - Oral History of Rudolph Schaeffer interviewed by Margaretta K. Mitchell (Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley), 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer interviewed by Bernie Swadley, Oakland Museum, circa 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Staff Meeting, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, July 9, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Printed Material, 1906-1994, Series 9:; (Boxes 7-8, 15; 0.9 linear ft.)
  Printed material concerns the career of Rudolph Schaeffer, his school and former students, the San Francisco art scene, and general art topics.
  Additional printed material is included with Series 3: Subject Files and Series 6: Scrapbooks.
  9.1: Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1935-1942
  9.2: Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1920s-1986
  9.3: Produced by Others, 1906-1987
  - Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1935-1942, 9.1:
    Material produced by Schaeffer consists of articles and a book.
    - Articles, 1937-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Books (Box 7)
      - Flower Arrangement I (portfolio; photography by Ralph Young), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Sunset’s Flower Arrangement Book by Nell True Welch, Edited and Foreword by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1920s-1986, 9.2:
    This subseries includes items such as school catalogs, announcements and invitations.
    - Calendars of Events, 1955-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Catalogs and Course Announcements, 1920s-1984, undated, (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 17-23)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1920s-circa 1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Form Letters, 1933-1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Lecture Announcements, 1920s-1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Newsletter, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Press Release, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Sample Certificates, Stationery, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Special Event Announcements and Invitations, 1948-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Produced by Others, 1906-1994, 9.3:
    Printed material found here is about or mentions Rudolph Schaeffer and his school. Items of note are announcements of courses taught by Schaeffer in Piedmont and San Francisco prior to the opening of his school, theatre programs from productions with sets and some costumes designed by Schaeffer in the early 1920s.
    - About or Mentioning Rudolph Schaeffer (Box 7)
      - Announcements of Rudolph Schaeffer Summer School of Design and Handicraft/Rudolph Schaeffer Crafts and Art Studio (Piedmont, Calif.), California School of Fine Arts, 1916-1919, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Book, Miss Aunt Nellie: The Autobiography of Nellie C. Cornish, University of Washington Press, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Clippings, 1910s-1980s, undated, (5 folders; see also Box 15) (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
      - Exhibition Announcements, 1922-1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Lecture and Workshop Notices, 1916-1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1906-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Rudolph Schaeffer Collection (exhibition catalogs, etc.), 1976-1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Theater Programs (sets designed by Rudolph Schaeffer), 1920-1925, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - About/Mentioning Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design (Box 8)
      - Advertising, 1920s-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
      - Clippings, 1927-1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1928-1960, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, Miscellaneous Subjects (art-related), 1932-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Oversized Clippings About/Mentioning Rudolph Schaeffer, 1976-1980 (Box 15 (sol))
- Photographs, 1880s-circa 1988, Series 10:; (Boxes 8-10, 15, OV 18; 1.3 linear ft.)
  Additional photographs may be found in Series 3: Subject Files and Series 7: Scrapbooks.
  The series is arranged into 8 subseries:
  10.1: Artwork, circa 1907-1980
  10.2: People, 1880s-1980s
  10.3: Places, circa 1907-1983
  10.4: Events, 1937-1976
  10.5: Stage Designs, circa 1920s
  10.6: Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1910-circa 1988
  10.7: Photograph Album, undated
  10.8: Negatives, Slides, and Color Transparencies, circa 1958-circa 1969
  - Artwork, circa 1907-1980, 10.1:
    Photographs are of artwork, people, places, events, stage designs, and miscellaneous subjects. Artwork includes some designs by Rudolph Schaeffer, many samples of student work in various media, and views of exhibition installations.
    - Designs (Box 8)
      - Furniture, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Furniture (Columbus Manual Training School), circa 1907 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Metal Work (including jewelry), undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Installations (Box 8)
      - "Modern Art Pots for Flowers, Rudolph F. Schaeffer Crafts and Art Studio, Piedmont"), 1910s (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Rudolph Schaeffer Collection of Asian Art, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Rudolph Schaeffer Collection of Rocks, Kansas City, circa 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Student Exhibitions, Rudolph Schaeffer instructor (Box 8)
        - California College of Arts and Crafts; Schaeffer’s Crafts and Art Studio, Piedmont, circa 1910s (Box 8, Folder 24)
        - Cornish School?, circa 1920s (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1931-1932, 1978, undated, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 26-31)
      - Oriental Art Exhibition (at Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design), 1980 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Women’s City Club, San Francisco, Exhibition of Decorative Arts (designed by Rudolph Schaeffer), 1929 or 1930 (Box 8, Folder 33)